# FAHEEM AKRAM

faheem.akram.bscs@gmail.com — +92-309-6703575 — Lahore, Pakistan LinkedIn — GitHub — Portfolio

### PROFILE SUMMARY

A driven Computer Science graduate specializing in **AI** and **Machine Learning** with strong **Python** skills and **One Year experience**. Currently working as **Generative AI Engineer**. Experienced in applying machine learning algorithms to solve real-world problems. Eager to contribute to innovative AI projects and beyond.

### **EDUCATION**

### Comsats University Islamabad (BSCS)

2020 - 2024

Courses: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Data Structures and Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Database Management System, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Information Security, and Cloud Computing.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

AI Intern CorTechSols, Islamabad

Duration: June 2024 - Aug 2024

I was responsible for AI work which involved gathering, cleaning, and analyzing datasets to train machine learning models. As an internee, I also contributed to the Python back-end development team, where my role was to create RESTful APIs and manage databases.

Associate AI Engineer

Agile Loop, Islamabad

Duration: September 2024 - October 2024

I am working on full-scale AI featured application titled browser use which is focuses on automated browsing and data extraction. I am also working on Agents, LangChain, and developing RAG applications.

#### Generative AI Engineer

AUG AI, Lahore

Duration: October 2024 - Continue

I am working on full-scale AI featured application Agentic AI, Multiple Agents. Estimation of real estate construction costs.

### **PROJECTS**

- Identification of human values behind argument through Natural Language Processing (NLP). Tools and Technologies: Python, Spyder IDE, NLTK, VS Code, Google Colab, Contextual Analysis, NLP libraries.
- Browser Use AI Automation: Tools and Technologies: Agents, LangChain, FASTAPI.
- Rover Dental Clinic

 $Tools\ and\ Technologies:\ Agents,\ Livekit,\ TTS\ and\ STT\ realtime,\ Tool\ Calling,\ SMS\ agent,\ LangChain,\ LiveKit,\ FASTAPI.$ 

• Real Estate Cost Estimate

Tools and Technologies: Excel for deta cleaning, Prompt Engineering, RAG, ChatBot.

• Custom AI Agent

Tools and Technologies: Inbound and Outbound agent, LiveKit, Call recording through LiveKit.

• Form Filling Agent

Tools and Technologies: Multi Agents, Agent-to-agent(A2A) pipeline, Docs Filling Agent, Excel Filling Agent, LLMs Integration, Translation APIs Multi Language.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

ML Algorithms - Deep Learning - AI Libraries Frameworks - NLP - LangChain- LangGraph - Agents - Data Structure - Hugging Face - EDA - Matplotlib - Seaborn - Numpy - Pandas - NLTK - Transformers architecture - BERT and Robarta Models - Scikit-learn - MongoDB - Python - C++ - FastAPI - Django - Big Data Technologies - Docker - Postman - SQL - DynamoDB - no code n8n - Prompt Engineering - LLMs fine tuning - RAG - TensorFlow - PyTorch - Postgresql - Git - GitHub - AWS - Deployment(Streamlit, DigitalOcean, AWS) - HTML - CSS - React

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Won 2nd position in university-wide Final Year Project showcase.
- $\bullet$  presented the FYP in The University of Faislabad and COMSATS University Wah Campus and Gain 3rd position.